Shin Hwei Tan

Assistant Professor

Southern University of Science and Technology

tansh3@sustech.edu.cn

Webpage: http://www.shinhwei.com/

DBLP: https://dblp.uni-trier.de/pers/hd/t/Tan:Shin Hwei

Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=1eFjFs8AAAAJ&hl=en

Research Interests

My main research interest is on the field of software engineering, specifically on automated bug-fixing and software testing. I have proposed new methods and developed tools to facilitate dynamic code-comment analysis using test generation tool and automated repair of software regressions and Android apps. I am currently looking at methods in building the next generation automated bug-fixing approach.

Education

National University of Singapore, Singapore

Ph.D., School of Computing, August 2012-March 2018 CAP: 4.38/5.00

Thesis Topic: Design of Repair Operators for Self-Healing Software Systems

Adviser: Abhik Roychoudhury

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign, IL

M.S., Computer Science, May 2012

GPA: 3.91/4.00

GPA: 3.68/4.00

Thesis Topic: @tComment: Testing Javadoc Comments to Detect Comment-Code

Inconsistencies

Advisers: Darko Marinov, Lin Tan

B.S. (Hons), Computer Science, May 2010

Thesis Topic: Theories/Parameterized tests for JUnit

Adviser: Darko Marinov

Awards and Honors

- Dean's Graduate Research Excellence Award (2016)
- Google Anita Borg Memorial Scholarship (2015) for encouraging female presence in computing and technology.
- Research Achievement Award (2015)
- David J. Kuck Outstanding MS Thesis Award (2013)
- Singapore International Graduate Award (2012-2015)
- ACM-W Scholarship (2012) for attendance of conference for female researchers
- Malaysian Government Scholarship (2006-2010)
- Rockwell Collins Scholarship (2009)
- Motorola Academic Scholarship (2008)

Services

- Maintainer of a blog, https://cstrigirls.blogspot.sg/, that focuses on giving academic advices to female computing students in Asia-Pacific countries.
- Mentor in Women in Engineering in University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign
- Coach for National Student Contest for Software Testing Competition in China
 - o My student won first prize in the contest

Conference /Workshop Publications

- 1. Y. Wang, M. Wen, R. Wu, Z. Liu, <u>S.H. Tan</u>, Z. Zhu, H. Yu and S.C Cheung. *Can I Have a Stack Trace to Examine the Dependency Conflict Issue?* In: International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2019), May 2019. (acceptance: 20.6%)
- 2. X. Gao, <u>S.H. Tan</u>, Z. Dong, and A. Roychoudhury. *Android Testing via Synthetic Symbolic Execution*. In 33rd IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE 2018). (acceptance: 19.9%)
- 3. <u>S. H. Tan</u>, Z. Dong. X. Gao, A. Roychoudhury. *Repairing Crashes in Android Apps*. In: International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2018), May 2018. (acceptance:

- 20.9%)
- 4. J. Yi, U.Z. Ahmed, A. Karkare, S.H. Tan, A.Roychoudhury. *A Feasibility Study of Using Automated Program Repair for Introductory Programming Assignments*. In: Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE 2017), Sept 2017. (acceptance: 24.4%)
- 5. S. H. Tan, H. Yoshida, M. Prasad and A. Roychoudhury. *Anti-patterns in Search-based Program Repair*, In:Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE 2016), Nov 2016 (acceptance: 27.1%)
- 6. <u>S. H. Tan</u>, A. Roychoudhury. *Relifix: Automated Repair of Software Regressions*. In: International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2015), May 2015 (acceptance: 18.5%)
- 7. J. Yi, D. Qi, <u>S. H. Tan</u>, A. Roychoudhury. Expressing and Checking Intended Changes via Software Change Contracts. In: International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA 2013), Lugano, Switzerland, July 2013. (acceptance: 26%)
- 8. S. H. Tan, D. Marinov, L. Tan, and G. T. Leavens. @tComment: Testing Javadoc Comments to Detect Comment-Code Inconsistencies. In: International Conference on Software Testing, Verification, and Validation (ICST 2012), pages 260-269, Montreal, Canada, April 2012. (acceptance: 27%)

Workshop/ Poster Publications

- 1. B. Baudry, N. Harrand, E. Schulte, C. Timperley, S. H. Tan, M. Selakovic, E. Ugherughe. *A spoonful of DevOps helps the GI go down.* In 4th International Genetic Improvement Workshop, May 2018.
- 2. <u>S. H. Tan</u>, J. Yi, Yulis, S. Mechtaev, A. Roychoudhury. *Codeflaws: A Programming Competition Benchmark for Evaluating Automated Program Repair Tools*. In: International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2017 Poster), May 2017.
- 3. B. Daniel, D. Dig, T. Gvero, V. Jagannath, J. Jiaa, D. Mitchell, J. Nogiec, <u>S. H. Tan</u>, and D. Marinov. *ReAssert: A Tool for Repairing Broken Unit Tests*. In: International Conference on Software Engineering, Demonstrations Track (ICSE Demo 2011), pages 1010-1012, Honolulu, HI, May 2011. (acceptance: 37%)

Journal Publications

- 1. S. Mechtaev, X. Gao, S. H. Tan, A. Roychoudhury. *Test-equivalence Analysis for Automatic Patch Generation*. In ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), To appear, July 2018
- 2. J. Yi, <u>S.H. Tan</u>, S. Mechtaev, M. Boehme, A.Roychoudhury. A correlation study between automated program repair and test-suite metrics. In: Empirical Software Journal (EMSE 2018).
- 3. J. Yi, D. Qi, <u>S. H. Tan</u>, A. Roychoudhury. *Software Change Contracts*. In ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), pages 18:1-18:43, May 2015.

Professional Activities

- ICSE 2020, Program Committee
- ASE 2019, Program Committee
- ESEC/FSE 2019, Tool Demo Program Committee
- ICSE 2019, PC for Student Research Competition
- Genetic Improvement Workshop (GI 2019) @ ICSE2019, Co-organizer
- GECCO 2018, PC for Genetic Improvement Workshop
- ISSTA 2014, Artifact Evaluation Committee
- ICSE 2015 (NIER), Co-reviewer
- Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), Reviewer
- Empirical Software Engineering Journal (EMSE), Reviewer
- Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE), Reviewer

Teaching Experience

Southern University of Science and Technology, China

Sole Instructor for CS 409 Software Testing

Aug. 2018 to Dec. 2018

- Proposed the first course in Software Testing in SUSTech
- Design course syllabus and prepared teaching materials
- Design course project for finding bugs in open-source Android apps

National University of Singapore, Singapore

Teaching Assistant for CS 4218 Software Testing

Aug. 2012 to May 2013

- Designed courses structure and prepared material for first software testing class
- Graded weekly programming homework

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign, IL

Teaching Assistant for CS242: Programming Studio Laboratory Aug. 2011 to May 2012

• Supervised programming assign' ments presentation for 5-6 students per section

Teaching Assistant for CS427: Software Engineering I Aug. 2010 to May 2011 Fall 2010 and Fall 2011

- Advised students for course project for Eclipse refactoring engines
- Graded bi-weekly programming assignments for 20 groups of students

Teaching Assistant for CS428: Software Engineering II
Spring 2011

Jan. 2010 to Dec. 2011

- Provided support for online students through the Illinois Internet Computer Science Program (I2CS)
- Conduct bi-weekly meeting with students for course projects to develop games, mobile applications, websites.

Laboratory Helper for CS 102: Little Bits to Big Ideas

Aug. 2009 to May 2009

- Assisted non-majors in two consecutive laboratory sessions
- Graded student programming assignments

Invited Talks

Conference Talks

Repairing crashes in Android apps	24 Nov. 2018
Program Repair Workshop@NASAC	
Repairing crashes in Android apps	17 Nov. 2018
Chinese Search-based Software Engineering Workshop	
Repairing crashes in Android apps	16 Nov. 2018
Peking University	
Repairing crashes in Android apps	22 June 2018
Wuhan University	
Repairing crashes in Android apps	30 Jan. 2018
GI-Dagstuhl Seminars, Germany	
Design of Repair Operators for Automated Program Repair	30 Jan. 2017
50th CREST Open Workshop, University of College London	
Anti-patterns in Search-based Program Repair	20 Sept. 2016
Microsoft PhD Forum 2016, Microsoft Research Asia, Beijing, China	
Anti-patterns in Search-based Program Repair	17 Nov. 2016
Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE) 2016	
Relifix: Automated Repair of Software Regressions	21 May 2015
International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE) 2015	
@tComment: Testing Javadoc Comments to Detect	19 April 2012
Comment-Code Inconsistencies	-

International Conference on Software Testing, Verification & Validation (ICST) 2012

Working **Experience**

NUS-Singtel Cyber Security Research and Development Lab, Singapore

Research Assistant

Nov. 2017 to May 2018

• Core developer and inventor for automated repair of crashes for Android apps **Fujitsu Laboratories of America**, Sunnyvale, CA, USA

Research Intern

Feb. 2015 to May 2015

- Conduct study of the common characteristics of automatically generated patches
- Developed techniques for improving search-based automated program repair

Intel Corporation, Penang, Malaysia

Summer Intern for Testing Hole Resolution (THR)

June 2011 to Aug. 2011

- Developed automation for improving efficiency in running automated tests
- Implemented features and developed error handling for program in Perl and Tcl

Railroad Department,

Champaign, IL, USA

Undergraduate Assistant

Aug. 2007 to May 2009

Carried out an independent project on automated web retrieval Maintained MS Access database for daily tank car accident reports Debugged and programmed using Visual Basic, Ruby and HTML

Software Skills

- Computer Programming: Java, Python, C, C++, OCAML
- Version Control: DVCS (Mercurial, Git), and VCS (CVS, SVN)
- Software Testing: Randoop, JUnit, KLEE

Language Skills

Fluent in Mandarin, Cantonese, English and Malay